hey guys this was a question on a
practice sat I kind of liked it because
there's two different ways you can solve
it so let's do it both ways the first
method uses these notes you can find the
area of any triangle if you know two
sides and the angle in between them the
area is equal to 1/2 time one side time
the other side time the sign of the
angle so for this triangle the area is
12 * 6 * 8 * the S of 60 and if you know
your unit circle you can just plug this
into calculator and get 12 < TK 3 and
this is the first method it uses this
shortcut so let's say you didn't know
this shortcut there is another way you
can do it I want to drop an altitude and
that's going to be perpendicular to this
side right here so if we focus on this
triangle right here since this angle is
90 and this one is 60 the last one is
going to be 30 so we are going to need a
different set of notes for this
specifically the 30 60 90 triangles in
any 306090 triangle the hypotenuse is
always twice as long as the shortest
side and the other side isare < TK of 3
* the shortest side so if we label this
side n the hypotenuse will be 2 N and
this last side is going to be n * the of
3 so this side is both 6 and 2 N so that
means the N is going to be equal to 3
and that means this altitude right here
is going to be 3 < tk3 and now we're
ready to use the area formula area is
equal to 1 12 base time height well the
base of this triangle is the 8 and the
height is the 3 < tk3 8 * 3 is equal to
24 and 1 12 of 24 is 12 so we have the
area is 12 < TK 3 and we got to give it
a unit squared so both methods gave us
the same answer how exciting